Sivaram G S

Senior Data Science Engineer | MS - Data Science | US Patent - 11256553

PROFILE

Enthusiastic and experienced Data Scientist with a strong background in delivering advanced analytics projects, leveraging mathematical modelling, machine learning, Generative AI and big data analysis. Aiming to leverage my experience in driving high-performing data science teams, delivering exceptional value to business users, and promoting advanced analytics practices and continuous innovation for Emirates.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Overall, 7.7 years of experience in data science domain driving the initiatives of results-driven analytics solutions end to end.
- Proven track record as Scrum Master with over 4 years of experience in agile delivery and project management.
- Skilled in guiding cross-functional teams, optimizing workflows, and delivering advanced analytical projects in complex organizational environments.

WORK EXPERIENCE

EVERTZ INDIA, BENGALURU

SENIOR DATA SCIENCE ENGINEER APRIL, 2020 – MARCH 2024 (PRESENT)

- Core member of the team that built and launched evGPT a chatGPT for Evertz powered by Large Language Models (GPT 3.5 Turbo, GPT-4) using Azure OpenAI.
- Collaborating with different product owners to ingest quality data and finetuned the LLM.
- Delivered analytics solution for the major sports leagues: NBA, MLB, NHL by applying statistical and machine learning techniques on the first party data collected by Evertz Easelive interactive graphics platform.
- Created online documentation of Easelive analytics for customer reference: https://docs.easelive.tv/analytics/index.html.
- Strong expertise in building & optimizing data pipelines to read large structured, semi-structured and unstructured data and store it in destinations like snowflake, databricks, postgreSQL.
- Designed, configured, and owned inSITE (Evertz Bigdata Analytic Solution) for different customers: DU Samacom (UAE), Fox (US), Rogers (Canada).
- Did extensive research and proposed a design to build a Fan Loyalty Solution and Customer Data Platform of Evertz with opensource tools.

DELL EMC. BENGALURU

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 1 JUNE, 2017 – MARCH 2020

- Part of DELL's Digital Lifecare that powers the Govt of India's Ayushman Bharat scheme for preventive screening of diabetes, hypertension, and cancers.
- Worked on data cleaning and analytics to detect fraudulent signatures in users' data collected by Primary Health Centres workers.
- Responsible for integrating and defining containerization of DELL EMC Solutions Enabler Product.
- US Patent-11256553 granted for research work "INTELLIGENT SYSTEM TO PRIORITIZE SERVERS FOR ENVISAGED REQUESTS"

TATA ELXSI, BENGALURU ENGINEER JULY, 2016 – JUNE 2017

CONTACT

Place: Chennai, India. Mobile: (+91) 9578131692 Email: sivaramgs@outlook.com

Profile: www.linkedin.com/in/sivaram-gs

EDUCATION

Master of Science (Data Science), Liverpool John Moores University. (Merit) (2020-2022)

Bachelor's (CS Engineering), Anna University, India. (First Class) (2012 – 2016)

CERTIFICATIONS

- ✓ AWS Quest Machine Learning
- ✓ AWS Quest Data Analytics
- ✓ AWS Quest Solution Architect
- ✓ AWS Quest Serverless Developer
- ✓ AWS Quest Security
- ✓ AWS Quest Cloud Practitioner

Link: Credly Badges

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

Functional

- Scrum Master Responsibilities
- Team Leadership
- Stakeholder Communication
- Collaborative Problem Solving
- Customer Experience
- Big Data Analytics
- Mathematical Modelling
- A/B Testing
- Users Segmentation
- Funnel Analysis

Tools

Jira, Confluence, Notion, Power Bl.

Platforms

AWS, Azure, Databricks, Snowflake.

Technologies / Frameworks

Machine Learning, Deep Learning, NLP, LLM, GenAl, ELK, Python, R, CI/CD, GIT, Docker, PostgreSQL, Hadoop, Spark, Mlflow, Kafka, Tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch, OpenAl, Langchain, Chainlit, Pinecone, PGVector, Streamlit, Plotly.